[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "question": "What projects are you working on at the moment?",
    "answer": "<ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>Been looing at the <strong>VueJS Framework</strong> and built a small utilily app for my own use to track tasks. (Model-View-ViewModel (MVVM) architectural pattern)</li><li>I recently built a <strong>'Stranger Things'</strong> Quiz in latest Angular. After watching the TV show with my daughters I want to let them test there knowledge - deployed yo GitHub Pages.</li><li class='list-disc list-inside'>I have been going back over my personal site increasing <strong>unit tests</strong> and was going to add some <strong>E2E tests</strong> to get familiar with <strong>Cypress</strong> as have I only used Protractor in the past.</li><li>Also adding some additional features like  <strong>login</strong>,  <strong>accordian</strong> with search.</li><li class='list-disc list-inside'>Aswell as looking at any accessibilty issues and resolving using lighthouse (axe DevTools & <strong><a class='underline text-tealy-500' href='https://codelabs.developers.google.com/angular-a11y#0A11y' target='_blank'>A11y</a></strong>- build more accessible Angular sites with the help of the <strong>Google Codelabs</strong> checklist).</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "question": "What is your general workflow when working on a feature or project. (SDLC)?",
    "answer": "<strong>Waterfall:</strong> <ul class='list-decimal list-inside'><li>Requirement analysis ></li><li>Design ></li><li>Implementation ></li><li>Verification ></li><li>Maintenance ></li></ul><br /> <strong>In respect to Agile</strong> <ul class='list-decimal list-inside'><li>Project planning ></li><li>Product roadmap creation ></li><li>Release planning ></li><li>Sprint planning ></li><li>Daily meetings ></li><li>Sprint Review</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "question": "What do you know about SEO in angular apps?",
    "answer": "<strong>Some SEO benefits to using SSR or Universal:</strong> <ul class='list-decimal list-inside'><li>Faster page loading</li><li>Search engine indexing/crawling</li><li>Better user experience generally</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "question": "How would you handle CSRF security issues in SPA apps?",
    "answer": "<strong>Cross-site Request Forgery</strong><ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>Passing CSRF tokens cookie on each request</li><li>Check on server side to authenticate token and allow form submission.</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "question": "Why Did You Choose a Career in Software Development?",
    "answer": "<strong>Problem solving</strong><ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>I like solving problems and I feel that development gives me the oppotunity to do that daily and enjoy the rewards that come fro that. I gain satisfaction in helping clients, companies, and organizations find solutions to there requirements. Additionally, I have experience with a variety of programming languages and enjoy working with them. For example, while I was at esure, I built their first native app for the Sheilas Wheels brand using the hybrid framework ionic. This used a headless CMS that the marketing department was able to update the content of th app from without developer input.</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "question": "What Programming Languages Are You Proficient In?",
    "answer": "<strong>Example anwser</strong><ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>I first learned how to use JavaScript, CSS, and HTML whilst working in my previous career and building small sites from local businesses and friends. I built a e-commerce site in FLASHMX in my earlier days too and went on to rebuild that site in ASP to improve SEO. Moving on, I started using things like, jQuery, PHP, SCSS as well as learning to use the ionic framework, that was when I was first introduced to the world of NPM. I built out a native app for a Shelias Wheels Brand usinf a Drupal as headless CMS. Currently spending most of my time on the Angular framework.‚Äù</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "question": "Can You Describe the Steps Involved in Software Development?",
    "answer": "<strong>Short anwser</strong><ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>Planning & Requirement gathering</li><li>Timeframes, Tools and team if applicable</li><li>Design</li><li>Iterate</li><li>Implementation of code</li><li>Testing</li><li>Deployment</li></ul><br /><br /><ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>Initial planning and brainstorming is the first step in software development. I would take part in the working out of the purpose/functionality required.</li><li>Next, involves team analysis, including the time frame and which tools and team members are needed if not working lone.</li><li> Then comes the design stage, where a program is designed by a team of software engineers/UI Designers before moving on to the development stage. </li><li>Once in development, I step in to transform the design into functional software. </li><li>It's then off to quality assurance to identify any defects or bugs.</li><li>Lastly, the software is officially installed and deployed using a planned CI/CD strategy.</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "question": "Tell Me About a Software Development Project You Completed Successfully?",
    "answer": "<strong>At esure</strong><ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li>, where I worked as a full stack developer, we developed thier first customer account dashboard for insurance customers, they were then able to update parts of their policy with us and access documents pertaining to each policy. I took part in coding the dashboard widgets and other parts of the site and implementing unit tests and E2E tests along the way. Mainly working Angular 4+ and the NodeJs middle for constructing data coming from the legacy backend. The final product helped customer to access information and make changes to their policy, which otherwise, they would have had to call the call center to achieve.</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "question": "How Do You Ensure Quality and Fix Errors?",
    "answer": "<strong>Testing / Peer Reviews</strong><ul class=\"list-disc list-inside\"><li>Unit testing</li><li>End-2End testing</li><li>Peer reviews of code</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "Can You Differentiate Between Functional and Object-Oriented Programming?",
    "answer": "<ul class=\"list-disc list-inside\"><li>Functional programming relies on mathematical functions, whereas object-oriented programming relies on classes of objects closely associated with functions. When using functional programming, you must work solely with functions. Object-oriented programming, on the other hand, allows you to store functions/methods within objects.</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "question": "How do you build for accessibility?",
    "answer": "<strong>Implement the following</strong><ul class=\"list-disc list-inside\"><li>Try to meet WCAG 2.0, and ARIA 1.2, and pass axe and Lighthouse accessibility audits</li><li>Test during development using axe DevTools and lighthouse</li><li>Fix low-color contrast issues</li><li>Use semantic HTML</li><li>Add ARIA support for screen readers</li><li>Angular CDK a11y package</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "question": "What steps do you take to mitigate preformance issues in Angular Application",
    "answer": "<strong>Implement the following</strong><ul class=\"list-disc list-inside\"><li><strong>OnPush change detection strategy</strong> : we can tell Angular not to check each component, every time the change detection runs.</li><li><strong>Detach Change Detection/NgZone</strong> :This technique can save a lot of time and improves performance for the objects where we don't need to check for changes every time some change occurs.</li><li><strong>Pure Pipes</strong></li><li><strong>Lazy Loading Modules - Preloading Modules</strong></li><li><strong>AOT Compilation (default since Angular 9)</strong></li><li>more yes...</li></ul><br /><strong>Implement the following</strong><ul class=\"list-disc list-inside\"><li><strong>Webkit bundle Analyzer</strong> to help optimize your odules and see if there are any issues or stuff your not using.</li></ul>"
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "question": "SCRUM",
    "answer": "Scrum Roles:<ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li><strong>Product Owner</strong></li><li><strong>Scrum Master</strong> </li><li><strong>Development Team</strong></ul><br />Scrum Artifacts:<ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li><strong>Product Backlog</strong></li><li><strong>Sprint Backlog</strong> </li><li><strong> Product Increment</strong></li></ul><br />Scrum Events:<ul class='list-disc list-inside'><li><strong>the Sprint</strong></li><li><strong>Sprint Planning</strong> </li><li><strong>Daily Scrum</strong></li><li><strong>Sprint Review</strong></li><li><strong>Sprint Retrospective</strong></li></ul>"
  }
]
